I'd like to know, and everybody listening
would like to know, I suppose, first of
all, what was the program? And then why
did you submit it to a clinical trial? And
how did you get scientists to participate
in that? Well, you took that complexity
and made it equally complex. Yeah, thanks,
sir. Thank you. I appreciate it. was
actually really simple. You know, I've
been working with people. This is gonna be
my
forty-eighth year of beginning now, across
the world. I have the privilege of
Recognizing there's only so many patterns.
While the brain has infinite complexity,
it's not completely complex in terms of
the mind. And so over the years I've
developed a series of processes to help
people kind of develop what is their true
north for them, not for me, and shift
their values so that they're naturally
pulled
in the direction of what they really want
at this stage, as opposed to what their
conditioning has to do with. And so, as
you well know, we don't experience life,
we
experience the life we focus on.
In every moment, what's wrong is always
available, so is what's right. And it's
not
positive thinking, it's about
intelligence. If you're in a lousy state,
you don't
treat people better, you don't perform
better, you're obviously not happier. So
what
we teach people is how to shift their
focus, how to determine what values at
this
stage of your life are the ones that are
most important to you that will pull you
towards what you want. I always look at
motivation, and I and I don't like the
word
motivation, but people overuse it, so I
might as well use it because I'm not a
motivator, I'm a strategist.
But I also believe in the power of
inspiring people, obviously, and having
high
energy. But you know, there's two types of
motivation. There's push motivation, as
I'm sure you know. That's where you're
using willpower and making yourself do it.
And you know, Jordan, you have an enormous
amount of willpower. My respect for you
is through the roof, all that you've dealt
with and all that you've done. And it's
helped shaped who you are, because you
haven't given up and move forward. But
there
is a limit to willpower. I got a lot of
willpower too. So but there's no limit to
pull motivation. Pull motivation is where
it's something that
You care about more than yourself,
something that's a magnificent obsession,
something where you're contributing. It
could be your kids, it could your family,
but all that ties to the aim of your
values that move you forward. And so we
have a
six-day process I do called Date with
Destiny. And by the way, if your viewers
ever
want to get a feel for it, there's a
documentary on Netflix called Tony
Robbins, I'm
not your guru, because I'm not here to be
your guru. but it'll give you like an hour
and forty-five minute walkthrough, and
it's pretty dramatic. And the name of it
again?
Tony Robbins, I'm not your guru. It's on
Netflix. And you see me deal with people
that are that are suicidal and turning
them around. And then you see us follow up
four years later. So you see it last,
because most people wouldn't think it
lasts if
you could make a change that quickly. So
how does that relate to the study? Well,
two professors, as I understand it, we
were approached by Stanford, and they said
two of our professors had come here. They
were clinically depressed and they're off
medication. And all they did was go to
this six-day program. We don't understand
it.
do you have data on this? And I said,
sure, I've got.
Millions of testimonials. And so they
said, no, scientific data. I said, no,
that's
not been my focus. My focus is just to get
results for people. But if you want to do
one, I'm open to it. What would you like
to study? And they said, well, right now
is
the middle of COVID. And they said, you
know, depression is through the roof,
suicide's through the roof, overdoses are
through the roof. I said, I know. And they
said, we'd love to test this non-
pharmological approach to it that you have
and see
what it really produces, because this
seems miraculous. And I said, Well, it's
not
miraculous, it's just rewiring the way in
which people perceive their world. If I'm
going to go
Do the Dakar race where I'm gonna go you
know, nine thousand miles to the Sahara
Desert, you can't take the car you're
currently running and expect it, you're
gonna
you're gonna die in the desert. You need
to have that car reengineered. So for
example, the exhaust can get above the
sand. Well, we help people re engineer and
we
don't tell them what to do. We show them
how to re engineer themselves. So they
have
their own autonomy and ownership. And I
said, but tell me something, if we're
gonna
study this, what do the meta studies show?
And the meta studies show that they said
that 60% of the people who come for
treatment, whether it's drugs or therapy
or both, 60% make no improvement. That's
the average. 40% improve overall. The
average improvement is 50%. So I said, So
they're half as depressed as they were.
They said, Yeah, some people get well, but
most people are on drugs for the rest of
their lives. And I said, You can almost do
that with a placebo. And the guy had a
nervous laugh and he said, Well, yeah,
maybe.
I said, Well,
I said, I'm sure it sounds like hubris,
but I said, just based on history, I'm
sure
we'll do better than that. I said, what's
the best study what of all psychiatry
you've ever seen in terms of wiping out
these symptoms? And at the time they said
there was a study done at Johns Hopkins,
you're probably familiar with it, five
years ago, where for a month they gave
people psilocybin, magic mushrooms, and
cognitive therapy. And they said the
results were the greatest in the history
of
psychiatry. At the end of six weeks, it
was their evaluation.
That group had 54% of the people had no
symptoms whatsoever of depression. I said,
Well, that's a great standard. I said, I'd
like to see us beat that. I said, again,
it doesn't sound sounds like Kubra's, it
sounds like maybe arrogance. I'm not
coming
from that place. I just think our numbers
will be significantly higher. But we'll
see. You designed the program. So they
designed it, and as you said, they had a
separate group that was just like they did
for Johns Hopkins, you know, test group
that didn't have my work. They had
gratitude journaling, they did various
other
things. And
The results were beyond their imagination.
At the end of six weeks, after just going
through a seminar, no drugs, no one-on-one
therapy, just the rewiring for
themselves, 93% of them had no symptoms
whatsoever. It's nothing like it has ever
been done. And they published it in the
journal of psychiatrists. Do you have any
idea? Has there been any longer-term
follow-up of There has been. Oh, there
has.
Yes, yeah. And seven percent of the people
still improve, but they didn't completely
eliminate their symptoms. But here's the
best part 19% came in with suicidal
ideation.
Zero suicidal radiation afterwards, which
is what I've seen over and over the
decades. So they followed up a year later
and they found 52% increase in positive
emotions, 71% decrease in negative
emotions a year later. And now they've
done
additional studies. They just did a one-
year study with 1,500 people. So you can
appreciate this. It's like a biggest study
you can imagine. 750 in each group. And
this one is on engagement in business and
in life, because
Right now, since COVID, the engagement
levels have gone through the floor. You're
probably familiar with it. They have three
measurements. One is, you know, are you
engaged? And engagement equals EBITDA or
equals profit in companies. You can see a
direct relationship. Then there's those
that are disengaged. That would be what
people started calling quiet quitting,
where they're doing the minimum they need
to.
And then there's actively disengaged,
which is actually people who are angry and
they're just trying to hurt the company
when they stay. That's not good. That's
definitely not good. And since COVID.
The drop in engagement is the biggest drop
in the history of any form of measurement
around the world. In addition, the largest
increase is an active disengagement.
Yeah, well, people's trust was violated.
That's right. They were angry. Yeah. And
so
they did a group and they haven't
published it, it'll come out shortly, but
I can
give you the broad strokes that's so
excited about is they eliminated all of
the
disengagement that had been d driven by
four years of isolation in six days.
And then the best part was without any
more interaction with me every month,
imagine
for a year, they increased in their
engagement. Oh, really? Because what's
happened
is now the hunger is awakened in them.
They now have a sense of control over
their
own life and same authors? different
group. The some of the same authors, some
additional group as well. UCLA is And that
big a difference in group size. Yes.
Because one of the criticisms of the study
obviously was that it was a
There was a small number of people. Well,
clinical studies are very, difficult to
do. So it's very easy to criticize a study
for having a small number, but it's very
difficult to run a better study.
Are you tired being held back by one size
fits all healthcare? Of having your
concerns dismissed or being denied that
comprehensive lab work you need to truly
understand your health? I want to tell you
about Merrick Health, the premier health
optimization platform that's
revolutionizing how we approach wellness
and longevity.
What sets Merrick apart isn't just their
cutting-edge diagnostic labs or concierge
health coaching, it's their commitment to
treating you as an individual. Their
expert clinical team stays at the
forefront of medical research, creates
personalized, evidence-based protocols
that evolve with you. Unlike other
services
that rely on cookie-cutter solutions,
Merrick Health goes the extra mile. They
consider your unique lifestyle, blood
work, and goals to craft recommendations
that
actually work for you.
Whether that's through lifestyle
modifications, supplementation, or
prescription
treatments. And with a remarkable 4.9 out
of five rating on Trustpilot, you know
you're in great hands. The best part is
you can get 10% off your order today. Just
head to MerrickHealth.com and use code
Peterson at checkout. That's
MerrickHealth.com code Peterson for 10%
off. Stop guessing and start optimizing
your
health today with MerrickHealth, because
your best life starts with your best
health.
Right, They've also done a study where a
separate one that they published in a
different journal that I can get to you,
which was about the teaching style. Cause
what they wanted to figure out is how does
this work. So I'll tell you what they
uncovered. There's a separate group that
have been working with them and had worked
on measuring my body on stage, because I
do immersion events. I think you know four
days, 15, 20,000 people in a stadium, 12,
13 hours a day.
And when COVID happened and they shut
everything down, I wanted to still help
people. So I built a studio because I kept
every stadium in the world was shut down.
And I started doing it with people in
their homes. So the first thing they did
is
during those first three and a half years
before COVID, they had been measuring me.
So they had me wear this 75,000 device
that measures everything. They take my
saliva
and my blood at every break. And they
found a whole crazy set of statistics.
Like,
you know, I burn 11,300 calories on stage
in a day. I didn't think that was
possible.
But consistently, that's my average. chess
masters, Jordan, I guess, burn about
thirty-five hundred to four thousand not
moving. And so before I even get on stage,
I burn about thirty-five hundred. I jump a
thousand times. I'm just standing there,
I'm going out the crowd, I'm running up,
and I keep the stadium engaged. Most
people
Won't sit for a three hour. It's like
watching a toddler play. Yeah. Well, I I'm
serious about Well, I'm serious about
that. Because you think about it, people
spend
three hundred million dollars on a movie
and go past three hours and you lost
everybody, right? And we have people from
193 countries, every country in the world.
So let's say Australia, we start here at
ten A.M. It's already midnight there. They
go from midnight
To one in the afternoon for four straight
days and nights and we lose six percent of
the people on average. It's mind boggling.
We've figured out how to keep people
engaged. So it's compelling and it's long
lasting. And here's the